Finding Aid for the Thomas J. Dodd Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Thomas J. Dodd Papers
Undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0112
1.68 linear_feet
Biographic Sketch Thomas J. Dodd
August 4, 1837 Born at Harper’s Ferry, Virginia
- Graduated from Transylvania University at Lexington, Kentucky, 1857
- Principal at the Academy at Millersburg, Kentucky, 1863
- Married, 1873
- President of Kentucky Wesleyan College, 1875-1876
- Professor Vanderbilt University School of Religion, 1877-1885
- Chair of Academic Department
- Taught Hebrew in the Biblical Department
- John Wesley -A Study for the Times - published, 1891
- Miracles - published, 1899
- Died at Christ Hospital, Cincinnati, Ohio, February 9, 1899
- Diary, May 19, 1873 - February 10, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- “Don’ts for Lovers and Young Married People”, Manuscript (Box 1, Folder 2)
- “Don’ts for Lovers and Young Married People”, Manuscript (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lectures - “Natural Law and Its Relations”, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Lectures - “Mental Faculties and Characteristics Most Essential to the Orator”, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lectures - Lexington Chatauqua, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Miracles (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Miracles of Jesus - Manuscript (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Sermons, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Sermons, 1873, 1874 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Sermons, 1874 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Sermons, 1874, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Sermons, and Sermon Fragments (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Vanderbiltiana # 1-4, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- John Wesley - A Study for the Times, September 1891, Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Sermons, 1873, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Sermons to the Children, 1873, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Sermons December, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Excerpts of Sermons (Box 4, Folder 2)